ENOCH OGUNRINDE

C# Developer

Lagos, Nigeria | +2347012227439 | ogunrindeenoch1@gmail.com

https://enochogunrinde.onrender.com

CAREER SUMMARY:

Motivated and solution-oriented C# developer with 2 years of experience developing and maintaining web applications and APIs using .NET and ASP.NET Core. Familiar with Entity Framework Core, and SQL server for data access and manipulation and Azure for cloud solutions. Strong problem-solving skills and a commitment to continuous learning and growth.

SKILLS:

- C#
- .NET
- ASP.NET core
- ASP.NET web api
- Microsoft SQL server
- Entity Framework core Blazor
- Dapper
- LINQ

- MVC
- Git
- Azure
- Debugging
- Database Management
- HTML and CSS
- Javascript

WORK EXPERIENCE:

LinkMeUp.

C# Developer Intern | February, 2022 - December, 2023

- Developed RESTful Apis for appointment scheduling and rescheduling.
- Improved customer service by implemented a real-time customer communication system using signalR.
- Tested development endpoints using swagger and postman.
- Assisted team in diagnosing and debugging production issues.
- Implemented an email notification system using Mailkit and Gmail smtp.
- Collaborate with other developers to update the website and create new features.

Amni International Petroleum Development Company Limited.

IT Technician | June, 2023 - August, 2024

- Troubleshot and resolved network connectivity issues for individual users and departments.
- Maintained optimal staff productivity by performing regular maintenance on computer systems, including software updates, security patches, and virus scans.
- Slashed paper cost 20% by implementing controlled printing for every staff with the use of password on printers.
- Provided technical support to staff members via telephone, email, or in-person visits.
- Maintained clean working environment by organizing cables, labeling devices, and keeping workstations tidy.
- Filed reports, gathered information, and performed research.

RELEVANT PROJECTS:

Appointment Scheduler

Freelance C# Developer

- Built a personal appointment scheduler with email and SMS remainder.
- Created using ASP.NET core Web API and EF Core.
- Implemented user registration and login, authentication, email verification, password reset, appointment scheduling/rescheduling.

RELEVANT PROJECTS:

- Integrated scheduled notification remainder to email and sms with Hangfire and Mailkit.
- HTML, CSS and Javascript used for apis/endpoints consumption.
- Azure SQL database used to store user and appointment details.

Zaptime Chat

Freelance C# Developer

- Built a real-time chat web app.
- Created using Blazor WebAssmebly and SignalR for real-time server to client communication.
- Utilized Entity Framework core and LINQ for data access and manipulation.
- Implemented real-time user status broadcast (online and ofline).
- Azure SQL database used to store user and message details .

EDUCATION:

2018 - 2022 | Landmark University

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science